Guide to the William H. Willis Travel Slide Collection, 1950s-1970s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
William H. Willis Travel Slide collection 1950s-1970s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Willis, William H.
3.0 Linear Feet 6000 Items
William H. Willis was Professor and Chair of the Department of Classics at Duke University.
Collection contains approximately 6000 travel slides from Europe, Asia, and the Middle East dating 1950s-1970s.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The William H. Willis Travel Slide Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift.
Biographical Note
William H. Willis was Professor and Chair of the Department of Classics at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Collection contains color slides from travel in Europe, Asia, and the Middle East with notable holdings from Greece and Turkey, are arranged first geographically and then by date. Original grouping for slide shows that were housed in carousels are maintained and noted.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Willis, William H.
Travel Photography
Europe -- Color slides
Asia -- Color slides
Middle East -- Color slides
Greece -- Color slides
Turkey -- Color slides
Contents of Collection
- Travel Slides, 1950s-1970s, (5 boxes)
  Arranged in slide boxes within larger storage boxes, except for box 5 which is only a single slide box.
  - Scotland, 1960 (Box 1.1)
  - England, 1959 (Box 1.1)
  - Portugal, 1967 (Box 1.1)
  - Spain, 1967 (Box 1.1)
  - France, 1970 (Box 1.1)
  - Netherlands, 1955 & 1957 (Box 1.1)
  - Netherlands, 1955 & 1957 (Box 1.2)
  - Netherlands, 1960 (Box 1.2)
  - Netherlands, undated (Box 1.2)
  - Netherlands, 1959-69, Slide Show Carousel #1 (Box 1.3)
  - Netherlands, 1959-69, Slide Show Carousel #2 (Box 1.3)
  - Netherlands, 1963 (Box 1.3)
  - Norway, 1958 (Box 1.4)
  - Norway, 1967 (Box 1.4)
  - Norway, undated (Box 1.4)
  - Sweden, 1958 (Box 1.4)
  - Finland, 1958 (Box 1.4)
  - Switzerland, 1957 (Box 1.5)
  - Italy, 1957 (Box 1.5)
  - Italy, 1957 (Box 1.6)
  - Italy, 1970 (Box 1.6)
  - Italy, 1971 (Box 1.6)
  - Italy, undated (Box 1.6)
  - Tunisia, 1970 (Box 1.6)
  - Czech Republic, 1958 (Box 2.1)
  - Croatia, undated (Box 2.1)
  - Greece, Special Showing undated (Box 2.1)
  - Greece, Special Showing undated (Box 2.2)
  - Greece, Thera & Santorini, 1971 (Box 2.2)
  - Greece, 1972 (Box 2.2)
  - Greece, Greek islands, undated (Box 2.2)
  - Greece, Greek islands, undated (Box 2.3)
  - Greece, Greek islands, undated (Box 2.4)
  - Greece, Mystras, undated (Box 2.4)
  - Greece, undated (Box 2.4)
  - Greece, undated (Box 2.5)
  - Greece, undated (Box 2.6)
  - Turkey, 1963-1964 (Box 2.6)
  - Turkey, 1963-1964 (Box 3.1)
  - Turkey, Istanbul Slide Show, 1964 (Box 3.1)
  - Turkey, Ephasus Slide Show, 1964 (Box 3.1)
  - Turkey, Ephasus Slide Show, 1964 (Box 3.2)
  - Turkey, Slide Show, 1964 (Box 3.2)
  - Turkey, Slide Show Carousel #1, 1968 (Box 3.2)
  - Turkey, Slide Show Carousel #2, 1968 (Box 3.2)
  - Turkey, Slide Show Carousel #2, 1968 (Box 3.3)
  - Turkey, Slide Show Carousel #3, 1968 (Box 3.3)
  - Turkey, 1968 (Box 3.3)
  - Turkey, 1968 (Box 3.4)
  - Russia, 1958 (Box 3.4)
  - Russia, 1958 (Box 3.5)
  - Egypt, Slide Show Carousel #1, undated (Box 3.5)
  - Egypt, Slide Show Carousel #2, undated (Box 3.5)
  - Egypt, undated (Box 3.6)
  - Egypt, undated (Box 4.1)
  - Jerusalem & West Bank, 1961 (Box 4.1)
  - Jordan, 1961 (Box 4.1)
  - Lebanon, 1961 (Box 4.1)
  - Syria, 1961 (Box 4.2)
  - Iran, undated (Box 4.2)
  - India, 1959 (Box 4.2)
  - India, 1959 (Box 4.3)
  - Sri Lanka, 1959 (Box 4.3)
  - Sri Lanka, 1959 (Box 4.4)
  - Nepal, 1959 (Box 4.4)
  - Burma, 1959 (Box 4.4)
  - Burma, 1959 (Box 4.5)
  - Thailand, 1959 (Box 4.5)
  - Cambodia, 1959 (Box 4.5)
  - Cambodia, 1959 (Box 4.6)
  - Hong Kong, 1959 (Box 4.6)
  - Japan, 1959 (Box 4.6)
  - Japan, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Brookfield Center, undated (Box 5)
  - Unknown, undated (Box 5)